<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../transforms/esr2html.xsl"?>

<ESR xmlns="http://common-criteria.rhcloud.com/ns/esr" name="Endpoint Detection Response(EDR)">
  
	<intro>
		<esrtitle>Endpoint Detection and Response (EDR)</esrtitle>
		<maintainer>NIAP</maintainer>
		<identifier>42</identifier>
		<version>1.0</version>
		<status>draft</status>
		<issuedate>March 05, 2018</issuedate>
		<approver/>
		<supercedes/>
	</intro>

	<section title="Background and Purpose" id="purpose">
		This document describes a core set of security requirements for Endpoint Detection and Response systems.
		These requirements cover basic security characteristics and behaviors for an EDR management server or service
		hosted in a cloud or on-premises (the EDR system).
		EDR Host Agent security requirements are addressed in the ESM-HostAgent Module Protection Profile.
		Evaluation against the resulting ESM-EDR and ESM-HostAgent Module Protection Profile (PP) will ensure that a fundamental 
		set of requirements are met. 
		<br/>
		The intent is that the remaining sections provide succinct statements that highlight the relevant aspects to be
		addressed by the Technical Community (TC) constructing the PP. Here, the authors provide a narrative that introduces
		the reader to the problem being solved, and presents key aspects that support or guide the TC, and may elaborate on
		subtleties not apparent in the “bulleted” high level statements.
	</section>
	<section title="Use Cases" id="usecases">
		The EDR system collects data from endpoint devices to enable the detection and remediation of potentially
		malicious endpoint system activity.
		<ul>
			<li>Detection of potentially unauthorized activity through the collection and analysis of endpoint data.</li>
			<li>Remediation of malicous activity, automated or otherwise, enabling an authorized user to respond to malicous activity.</li>
			<li>Discovery enabled through browse and query interfaces to explore collected host data and subsequent analyses.</li>
		</ul>
	</section>

	<section title="Resources to be protected" id="resourcesprotected">
    	<ul>
			<li>Sensitive data stored by the EDR system.</li>
			<li>Credentials for authentication to or from the EDR system.</li>
    		<li>Cryptographic key material used to perform secure communications with host agents.</li>
    		<li>Sensitive data in transit to or from the EDR system.</li>
		</ul>
	</section>

	<section title="Attacker access" id="attackeraccess"> 
	<ul>
		<li>An attacker is assumed to attempt attacks from the following vantage points:
			<ul>
				<li>The network across which the application engages in communication, both actively
				and passively.</li>
				<li>The platform on which the application is installed, though as an unprivileged
				subject.</li>
			</ul>
		</li>
		<li>An attacker has an arbitrary amount of time to analyze the behavior of the application,
		its interaction with its host device or platform, and/or the data it transmits over the network.</li>
	</ul>
	</section>
	
	<section title="Essential Security Requirements" id="requirements">
		The following are the essential security requirements expected to be implemented by an EDR system
		within the established scope.
		<ul>
			<li>The EDR system shall use established encryption techniques (hashing, signing, etc.) to assure:
				<ul>
					<li>Encryption of sensitive data in transit to or from any host agents (e.g., TLS)</li>
					<li>Confidentiality of connections to or from the management dashboard (e.g., TLS/HTTPS)</li>
					<li>Encryption, by the EDR system or underlying platform, of sensitive and persistently stored data collected from endpoints</li>
					<li>Confidentiality of all commands sent to host agents</li>
					<li>Integrity of all commands sent to host agents (tbd: objective or required)</li>
				</ul>
			</li>
			<li>The EDR system shall collect and store a minimum set of parameters and events
			from endpoint systems, including:
				<ul>
					<li>operating system version, internal/external host IP addresses</li>
					<li>privileged and unprivileged user account login activity</li>
					<li>process creation</li>
					<li>libraries and modules loaded by a running processes</li>
					<li>network connection activity, including destination URLs, IPs</li>
					<li>files created on persistent storage</li>					
				</ul>
			</li>
			<li>The EDR system shall provide the ability to label, tag, or categorize individual endpoint systems.</li>
			<li>The EDR system shall provide a visualization of an alert; including an alert timeline and severity assessment</li>
			<li>The EDR system shall support Role-Based Access Control 
				for the delegation of, at least, the following roles:
				<ul>
					<li>Administrator, or someone who fully exercises all EDR features</li>
					<li>SOC Analyst, or someone who can investigate, remediate, and close incidents</li>
					<li>Read Only, or someone who can only read data and cannot perform analysis actions</li>
				</ul>
			</li>
			<li>The EDR system shall protect dashboard credentials from harvesting and brute forcing</li>
			<li>The EDR system shall provide response and isolation capabilities, including at a minimum:
				<ul>
					<li>Endpoint network quarantine and isolation</li>
					<li>Endpoint process termination</li>
					<li>Retrieval of remote endpoint files (malicious artifact capture)</li>
				</ul>
			</li>
			<li>The EDR system shall provide an API or a data export mechanism using standards based formats
			(e.g., STIX) for integration into custom or third-party reporting software.</li>
			<li>The EDR system shall provide a configuration option for the retention period of collected data.</li>
			<li>The EDR system shall provide a configuration option to suppress false positives by file, folder, hash.</li>
			<li>The EDR system shall implement a minimum set of modern anti-exploitation features, including:
				<ul>
					<li>Address Space Layer Randomization (ASLR)</li>
					<li>Stack Canaries/Cookies</li>
					<li>Data Execution Protection (DEP)</li>
					<li>CSRF Tokens</li>
				</ul>
			</li>
		</ul>
	</section>

	<section title="Assumptions" id="assumptions">
		Simply put, this section presents the aspects of the product and its intended environment that
		can be assumed to hold true. This will provide additional scope on the resulting protection profile.
		<br/>
		The following assumptions are made for the EDR product and its operational
		environment:
		<ul>
			<li>Depending on configuration and capability, the product may or may not be:
				<ul>
					<li>Configuration-managed by the enterprise</li>
					<li>Bound to directory server or cloud environment to support multi-user login</li>
				</ul>
			</li>
			<li>The EDR system is connected to a network. For purposes of sending/receiving data host agent data. Other
				entities on the network are not inherently trustable. </li>
			<li>Administrators are not malicious in nature.</li>
			<li>Users are not malicious in nature, though they may inadvertently or intentionally engage in risky behavior.</li>
		</ul>
	</section>

	<section title="Objective Requirements" id="objective">
		<ul>
			<li>
				The EDR system shall collect and store:
				<ul>
					<li>All new hardware devices added to system (this might be an objective)</li>					
				</ul>
			</li>
			<li>
				The EDR system shall provide digitally signed command updates to the Host Agent
			</li>
			<li>
				The EDR shall perform client authentication to host agents using X.509v3 certificates.
			</li>
		</ul>
	</section>

	<section title="Optional Extensions" id="extensions"> 
	</section>

	<section title="Outside the TOE's Scope" id="outsidescope">
		The following list contains items that are explicitly out-of-scope for any evaluation
		against the product protection profile.
		<ul>
			<li>The hardware or firmware of the underlying platform</li>
			<li>The host operating system or cloud environment of the EDR system</li>
			<li>The underlying web server or cloud environment used by the EDR system</li>		
		</ul>
	</section>
</ESR>
